Gian Riyanto

Software Engineer

+61 406 073 200 li.griyanto@gmail.com U.S. Permanent Resident

Profile

Software engineer with a passion for products, people, and building delightful user experiences. Driven by my intellectual curiosity and strong growth-mindset, I enjoy the process of collaboratively transforming new learnings into meaningful contributions through code, software design, and products.

Personal Links

gianriyanto.com github.com/gianriyanto linkedin.com/in/riyantogian

Experience

Software Engineer

HelloFresh Jan 2021 - Present

- Built and delivered product features and services to continuously improve the operations and supply chain management platform.
- Developed scalable technical solution designs with maintainable, testable, and efficient implementations that directly deliver business and user value.
- Implemented domain driven design and engineering best practices to continuously improve code base, systems, processes, and software design.

Web Developer

Freelance Oct 2020 - Jan 2021

- Designed modern web applications to scale and transform client's business through delightful user experience solutions.
- Developed and deployed websites using Vue, Vuex, JavaScript, HTML, and pure s(css) to design UI components.
- Closely collaborated with clients to understand their business domain, process, and customer experience.

Software Engineer

LinkaAja Dec 2019 - Mar 2020

- Proposed and developed automated data pipeline using Apache Airflow DAGs to orchestrate data processes and workflows.
- Built end-to-end Airflow pipelines in python to automate various business needs and use-cases.
- Collaboratively built big data infrastructure and processes to ensure data and analytics is accurate and available for all stakeholders.

Technology Consultant

HR Path Nov 2018 - Jun 2019

- Configured SAP SuccessFactors projects based on the client's business process and requirements.
- Gathered, analysed and transformed client needs, insights and problems into tailored system solutions.

Education

University of Technology Sydney

Mar 2016 - Oct 2021

Bachelor of Engineering

Software (Honours)

Dean's List Engineering 2021

Technologies

JavaScript, Python

Vue, Vuex, React, Hooks

HTML, S(C)SS

Flask, Fast API, PyTest

PostGres, MySQL

MongoDB, FireBase

SQL, NoSQL

RESTful API

Apache Airflow

AWS, Docker, Concourse

Version Control, Git

Skills

UI/UX Design

Object Oriented Design

Domain Driven Design

Database Design

Systems Design

Software Observability

Test Driven Development

Testing and Debugging

Agile Development, Scrum

Software Projects

Consultgianti.com Web App

- Designed and developed a personal website for the founder of Aspectama, an education consulting firm.
- Streamlined and improved efficiency of client acquisition process
- Developed a digital presence with a modern and attractive medium to engage new clients.

Career Counsellor's Personal Websites Web App

- Designed and developed personal websites for education counsellors - consultchen.com, consultveve.com
- Improved client acquisition process with an experience that shortens the time-to-contact.

I OWE YOU Web App

- Built and deployed a favours-debt-tracking web application using MERN technology stack.
- Designed UI components and developed the front-end application.
- Received an honourable mention for its UI/UX design.

Cryptocurrency Dashboard Web App

- Built a live dashboard containing a collection of widgets that displays a range of data for a given cryptocurrency.
- Developed using Vue.Js, Vuex, and Chart.Js
- Designed UI components from scratch using SCSS

Teams Chat Web App

- A team communication channel and project management platform built using ReactJS, Node, and Firebase NoSQL database.
- Collaboratively worked with a team of 15 members using Scrum and Agile practices.

Analytics Dashboard Web App

- Developed a responsive analytics dashboard for users to manage, monitor, and analyse data at a glance.
- Worked as a front-end developer designing and implementing the dashboard interface with VueJS and ChartJS.

Interactive Login Page Feature

- Developed a responsive and interactive login type-form feature.
- · Built using VueJS, HTML, SCSS

Supervised Learning Project ML Model

- Implemented a machine learning classification algorithm to predict values of a dataset.
- Employed various data analytics processes, techniques and practices using python to improve efficiency, accuracy and performance.

Other Experiences

Software Engineering Virtual Experience

JPMorgan Chase & Co

Product Analyst

Mitra Cipta Agro

Programming Teacher Assistant

Code Camp

Nov 2017 - Nov 2018

Mathematics Teacher Assistant

Montessori Mathematics Tutor

Relevant Coursework

Core Engineering Subjects

Design and Innovation
Business Requirements Modelling
Systems Development Methodologies
Systems Testing and Quality Management
Entrepreneurship and Commercialisation
Engineering Economics and Finance
Engineering Project Management
Mathematical Modelling

Computer Science Subjects

Advanced Internet Programming
Applications Programming
Data Structures and Algorithms
Introduction to Data Analytics
Database Fundamentals
Object-Relational Database
Software Engineering Studios (6 part course)
Software Architecture